

katy.jane8@gmail.com510-332-8447Louisville, Colorado

★ katyjane8in kathrine-welyczko♠ katyjane8

SUMMARY

As a puzzle master and devoted coder, I love working with new languages and problems. I am highly analytical and process-oriented with in-depth knowledge of APIs and testing through extensive QA experience. I thrive in areas that need process improvement and a focus on efficiency from 5+ years of dedicated technical project management. I pick up new technologies quickly and work with my team to produce products customers love.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LANGUAGES TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS

Ruby Ruby on Rails
Java GraphQL
SQL Git
HTML5 React
CSS3 Docker

JavaScript Agile Development

SASS jQuery

Active Record Selenium CircleCI

EDUCATION

Turing School of Software & Design

August 2017 to April 2018

Logged over 2000 hours with emphasis in Ruby on Rails and JS applications consuming APIs

Ohio University

BA Women's Studies & Film 2005 Emphasis on writing and criticism

ACTIVITIES

TURING SCHOOL STUDENT ADVOCATE -

Leader in Imposters Lunch & Armstrong Posse Lead Facilitated group therapy sessions and coaching to overcome Imposter Syndrome. Helped students achieve success by fostering student support with mentorship opportunities.

GIRLS WHO CODE - LOUISVILLE, CO CHAPTER -

Co-founder and instructor

Taught 7-12th grade girls coding skills through games and real life applications, at the local library

GIRL DEVELOP IT - *Member - Boulder/Denver Chapter* Participated in classes and meet-ups to promote women in technology

THE LOUISVILLE FIBER ARTISTS - Moderator and Founder Weekly knitting and crochet group for women of all skill levels

EXPERIENCE

APTO

Software Engineer

Digital Producer

Denver, CO May 2018 to Apr. 2019

 Built a new custom integration for the product through the Mailchimp API

- Deliver feature work using React and GraphQL
- Unit test features using Jest and Mocha
- Write end to end automation tests in Java

VOLTAGE ADVERTISING & DESIGN

Louisville, CO Feb. 2017 to July 2017

- Coordinated \$5k \$100k web and design projects for clients such as Reebok and Urban Mattress, with QA for all deliverables
- Facilitated agile workflows with several clients concurrently, including budget updates and presented at weekly meetings with aggregate updates

CROCS Niwot, CO

 Associate Producer & QA Lead
 Mov. 2012 to Jan. 2017
 Managed go-to-market process within Basecamp, utilizing a combination Agile/Waterfall PM methodology

 Completed QA for on-site assets in HTML format through Sublime Text and Demandware

PROJECTS

BOOKISH (SOLO)

- A tracking app using Goodreads OAuth, Goodreads API, Google Geolocator/Places, NYT Bestseller List
- Created this dream app to keep track of my Goodreads queue while still supporting local bookstores
- Javascript, JQuery, Ruby on Rails, APIs
- https://are-you-bookish.herokuapp.com/ || https://github.com/katyjane8/bookish

KNIT-WITS (GROUP)

- Multitenancy e-commerce application selling handmade knits
- Executed plan of selling my handmade items, developed stellar Git workflow
- Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord, SASS
- https://knit-wits.herokuapp.com/ || https://github.com/katyjane8/knit-wits

JOB TRACKER (SOLO)

- Job tracking application utilizing measurable data to create aggregate information
- Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord, SASS
- https://github.com/katyjane8/job-tracker

IDEA BOX (SOLO)

- Platform for idea storage using authentication for validated users
- Ruby on Rails, Heroku, Paperclip
- https://idea-box-kjw.herokuapp.com/ || https://github.com/katyjane8/idea_box